<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Green Apple Pi]]></title>
  <link href="http://AdamBurch.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://AdamBurch.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-03T00:32:25-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://AdamBurch.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Adam Burch]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[p1d40n3@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Storms and Hostile Universes]]></title>
    <link href="http://AdamBurch.github.io/blog/2014/01/02/storms-and-hostile-universes/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-02T17:40:37-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://AdamBurch.github.io/blog/2014/01/02/storms-and-hostile-universes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every month, I pick up a couple new books for my Kindle. This month, I started diving into some fiction.</p>

<p>The books I picked up, <em>Implied Spaces</em> by Walter Jon Williams and <em>The Way of Kings</em> by Brandon Sanderson parallel each other in a very odd way. The overarching questions in both these books is <em>Yay we won! What now?</em></p>

<p>Both feature societies that have achieved something incredible for their people. <em>The Way of Kings</em> Alethi have united under the banner of an (assassinated) king. In <em>Implied Spaces</em> we find a humanity that has conquered death, and so had to make new universes in which we <em>could</em> die. Incredible, <strong>AMAZING</strong> things.</p>

<p>But those things are past. The days of reunification are over in the minds of the Highprinces of Alethkar. Now there&#8217;s <em>new</em> glory to be had! Mobs with the fattest of loot! Gemstones the size of your <strong>head</strong>![1]. And in sci-fi land, lacking mobs, humanity farmed realities instead.</p>

<p>This question hangs over the characters as well - Aristide of Earth is a wandering computer scientist-cum-swordsman, whose newfound purpose (stop his evil space twin from taking over humanity) kicks off the novel. Back in Roshar, we find the &#8216;Blackthorn&#8217;, Dalinar Kholin trying to cement his dead brother&#8217;s kingdom, and finding diplomacy a pain in the ass compared to combat.</p>

<p>This is really odd to me, as growing up all the stories I read where about the great things that WERE GOING TO HAPPEN! Sure, high fantasy has always had settings in the ruins of past greatness, but even then there was a focus on what was to come. The past was a signpost, something that had come and gone and held SECRETS. Now the past isn&#8217;t even past!</p>

<p>What really strikes me though is seeing this in SCI-FI. I always read about space exploration and expanding horizons. Reading about the post-singularity ennui/megalomania/immortality of humanity is a new experience.</p>

<p>Thanks books!</p>

<p>[1]I&#8217;m dead serious. Monsters that give magic gemstones on death are an actual major plot point. I&#8217;m liking this book!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://AdamBurch.github.io/blog/2013/12/31/new-blog/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-31T00:06:48-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://AdamBurch.github.io/blog/2013/12/31/new-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Alright, new projects new blog! My name is Adam David Burch, and I&#8217;m a programmer who&#8217;s passionate about videogames. This blog will primarily be about my videogame projects, although it could stray to any topic at any time - perils of a blog!</p>

<p>This blog will update every Wednesday and Friday. Stay tuned!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
